SHARMIK HIRPARA

Web Developer

PROFILE

Disciplined and enthusiastic web developer with 6-months experience as full stack developer. At Australian Computer Society, designed rule-based chatbot for real estate company. At Entrust ICT, refactored database and designed back-end and UI ahead of time and within the budget.

CONTACT

EMAIL:

sharmik.hirpara@gmail.com

I INKED IN:

www.linkedin.com/in/sharmik-hirpara

PORTFOLIO:

https://sharmik-hirpara.github.io

SOFT SKILLS



WORK EXPERIENCE

Vedaleon Technologies| Front-End Developer

April 2021 to present

- Writing clean, testable good quality websites using PHP and JavaScript.
- Collaborating with the seniors and other stakeholders to build efficient and reliable features.
- Taking part in code reviews and sharing knowledge with the rest of the team to support an environment of continuous learning.
- Learning new tools, technologies, and frameworks to help scale company's stack and help team achieve company's goals more efficiently.

Australian Computer Society | Front-End Developer

April 2021 to July 2021

- Wrote and maintained HTML5, CSS and JavaScript code to meet system requirements, system designs and technical specifications in accordance with quality accredited standards.
- Researched, consulted, analysed, and evaluated system program needs.
- · Performed documentation support functions.
- Lead and managed a Chatbot application development team of 10.
- Coordinated and leading the team meeting to discuss progress, team activities and agree on plans for the coming fortnight.

Entrust ICT | Web Developer

Aug 2019 to Oct 2019

- Gained critical analysis skill through understanding existing product management system.
- Wrote clean, well designed, efficient code using to best web development practices.
- Achieved project goal accurately and efficiently by applying data management skills while refactoring database.
- Designed and created the new website layout and user interfaces with standard PHP and JavaScript practices.
- Sharpened ownership and responsibility by reporting project status to the project supervisors and industry supervisor.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

CSS3 Java EE **NoSQL** Troubleshooting laptop/desktop PHPEmbedded C Power point Object-oriented programming ReactJS Python JavaScript Java OOP UI/UX Java Git debugging MS Access Word **PowerBI UML** GitHub Pascal AWS C++ XMI Java Server Faces PC maintenance

ACADEMIC PROJECT DETAILS

Web application for Gym **Role:** Individual project

Language: HTML5, PHP, CSS3,

JavaScript, MySQL

Online shipping company web application

Role: Individual project

Language: PHP, CSS, JavaScript,

MySQL

Online bidding web application

Role: Individual project

Language: PHP, CSS, JavaScript, DOM

Interactive Dashboard for Smart Cloud

Manager

Role: Quality Assurance Analyst **Language:** Python, R, ReactJS

OTHER WORK EXPERIENCE

Citywide | Team Leader

May 2020 to May 2021

- Mentoring and encouraging a team consist of 20 members.
- Generating and sharing comprehensive and detailed reports about team performance to the supervisor.
- Creating roster and delegating tasks.
- Listening to team members' feedback and resolve any issues or conflicts.

EDUCATION

Master's in Information Technology

Swinburne University of Technology, Hawthorn, Australia. Feb 2018 to Nov 2019

Achieved GPA of 2.812 (4-point scale) during this course.

Bachelor of Engineering (Electronics)

Savitribai Phule Pune University, Pune, India.

Oct 2010 to Nov 2014